In my name, Euphemia li Britannia,
I order you all!
わたくし
ユーフェミア・リ・ブリタニアの
名の下に 命じさせていただきます
Please kill all those who
call themselves Japanese!
日本人を名乗る人々は
全て殺して下さい
１人たりとも残してはなりません
Not a single one must be left alive!
夢見てた夢
Yumemiteta yume
The dream that I dreamed
果て無き遠く
Hatenai tooku
Endless and distant
乾いた日々の 空色・手の中
Kawaita hibi no sorairo, te no naka
The sky-blue of dry days, in my hands
Toukankaku oto no naka de
In the space between each tick of the clock
等間隔 音の中で試行錯誤
Shikousakugo
Trial and error
時間・間隔の無い空間
Jikan kankaku no nai kuukan
A space without distance or time
等身大 音をたてて
Toushindai oto wo tatete
Making a life-sized sound
僕の顔　造って行く
Boku no kao tsukutte yuku
It defines my face
Kirei ni katahou dake
Cleanly, but only one side
キレイに　片方だけ
この手に落ちた
Kono te ni ochita
This rotting apple...
腐りかけのリンゴ
Kusarikake no ringo
That's fallen into my hand
鏡に映る　僕らの裏側まで
Kagami ni utsuru
Reflecting in the mirror
Bokura no uragawa made
Even showing our other side
Toukankaku oto no naka de
In the space between each tick of the clock
遠感覚 人の中で試行錯誤
Shikousakugo
Trial and error
時間・感覚の無い空間
Jikan kankaku no nai kuukan
A space without distance or time
Toushindai tsume wo tatete
With life-sized claws bared
頭身台 爪をたてて
Boku no kao wo kezutte yuku
I shave my face
僕の顔　削って行く
Kirei ni katahou dake
Cleanly, but only one side
キレイに　片方だけ
Toukankaku
A distant sensation
ー遠感覚
Toukankaku
A distant sensation
AT LEAST WITH SORROW
ユーフェミアは 我々を裏切った
全軍 式典会場に突入しろ！
Euphemia has betrayed us!
All forces, charge into
the ceremony grounds!
ブリタニアを粉砕するんだ
Smash the Britannians!
ユーフェミアめ！
騙し討ちをするなんて！
How dare that Euphemia!
How dare she trick us like this!
イレヴンがー！
ELEVENS!
そうか
That's right... I knew this
was your real intention!
やはり それが 本音か！
黒の騎士団だ！
It's the Black Knights!
ブリタニアをぶっ壊せ！
Smash the Britannians!
どこだ？
Where is she?! Where's Euphy?!
ユフィは どこに？
やめろ！　今 お前達に
かまっている暇はないんだ！
Stop it! I don't have time
to waste with you!
My! This has become a real mess.
わー もう 何が何やらぁ
許さない 皆の気持ちを踏みにじって
ユーフェミア！
How dare you! How dare you trample
on everyone's hopes like this...
Euphemia!
急げ！
やめろ！
Stop it!
いーっ
日本人ですか 無礼でしょ
Are you Japanese?
How rude of you!
I am Euphemia li Britannia!
わたくしは
ユーフェミア・リ・ブリタニアですよ？
えっ！
そうか ここにいたのか
お人形の皇女様
So, this is where you are...
The little puppet princess!
あら あなた あの島にいた…
Oh, you were on that island,
weren't you?
ああ みんなの仇 ここで…
Yeah... And I'm going to avenge
everyone, right here!
待て！
Wait!
あっ
彼女は 私がやる
I'll deal with her!
日本人のくせにっ
A Japanese dares do this?!
どうしますか？　ゼロ　捕虜に？
Now what, Zero?
Do we take her prisoner?
無駄だよ もう…
That's useless, now.
虐殺です 日本人は全て 皆殺しです
Kill them all!
I must kill all the Japanese!
えーっい
えっ えい
どうして？　早くっ　早く
Why now?! Quickly! Quickly!
えーっと 確か…
Umm... I think it goes like this.
は… あっ！
あら 日本人かと思っちゃった
Oh, I thought you were a Japanese.
ねぇ 考えたんだけど
一緒に行政特区日本の宣言を…
So, I was thinking, we can run the specially
administrated zone of Nippon together...
あら？　日本…
Nippon...
ああ できれば そうしたかった
Yes. I really wanted to, if I could.
君と共に
You and I.
あっ
ユフィ
Euphy...
はっ
あっ
どうして？　ルルーシュ
Lelouch... Why...?
さようなら ユフィ
たぶん 初恋だった…
Farewell, Euphy.
You may have been
the first girl I ever loved.
ぐわーあっ！
なっ
スザク？
Suzaku!
こんな時に！
Why now?!
くっ
ハドロン砲は受け止めきれない
I can't stand up
to that Hadron Cannon!
ルルーシュを殺させる訳には！
I can't let you kill Lelouch!
スザク！
Suzaku!
邪魔をするなぁー！
OUT OF MY WAY!!!
うっ このー！
You!
おっ！
あっ
お願いします　ユフィを…
Please... Save her! Save Euphy!
ユフィを助けて下さい！
ダールトンとは まだ連絡が
つかないのか
You still haven't made
contact with Darlton?!
はい 負傷されたとの報告ですが
その先は…
No, Your Highness. There was a report
he'd been injured, but nothing since then.
コーネリア総督
アヴァロンより緊急入電です
Viceroy Cornelia!
Emergency message from the Avalon!
アヴァロンから？
From the Avalon?
はい
Yes. The specially administrated zone
at Fuji has fallen to the Black Knights.
黒の騎士団によって
フジの行政特区が落とされたと
何？
What?!
黒の騎士団は 迎撃体制を整えています
The Black Knights are
moving to intercept our forces.
それと…
Also...
Princess Euphemia has been!
ユーフェミア様が…
ぬぉー うー
うぉー
To hell with "equality!"
To hell with your special zone!
何が平等だ！　行政特区だ！
よくも俺達を騙し討ちにしたな
もう許さねぇ
How dare you trick us like this!
We won't forgive this!
We'll never, ever forgive this!
ぜってぇに許さねぇからなあ！
そうだー！
That's right!
ブリタニアを許すなー！
Never forgive Britannia!
俺達は日本人だー！
We're Japanese!
良かったじゃなぁい
It's a good thing, isn't it?
この式典会場に
ムービーや機材が残ってて
The way they left these movies and machinery
behind here in the ceremony grounds.
ああ 編集後ネットにあげて
全世界に見せつけてやる
Yeah.
After it's edited, we'll upload it to the Net
and let the whole world see what happened.
どちらが正義なのかを分かりやすく
To make it easier to see
which side is the just one.
あんたってさ～あ ホント
ブリタニアへの忠誠心がないわねぇ
You don't feel any loyalty
toward Britannia, do you?
忠誠？
Loyalty?
うん
ブリタニアは完成した素材だ
そんなものに尽くして なんになる
Britannia is a closed book.
What's the point of
serving such a thing?
あっははっ 思ってたより
素直な人間ねぇ
You're a more honest man than I thought!
君こそ これからどうする
And what will you do now?
さぁねぇ
データが欲しかった だけなんだけど
Who knows?
All I wanted was data.
あんたら見捨てるのも気持ち悪いし
ゼロは面白い男だしねぇ
But I'd feel bad abandoning you all,
and I find Zero such an amusing man.
やっとお会いできましたね
At last, we meet!
この女
This girl...
確か スザクの親戚の…
I'm sure she's a relative of Suzaku's.
ゼロよ これからの事だが
わしらの下で
Zero, we want to make sure you'll be
working for us in what's to come...
逆だ！
Just the opposite!
ん？
こうなった以上 キョウト六家の方々は
私の指揮下に入って頂く
From here on, you of the six houses of
Kyoto will be acting under my direction!
反論は許さない
I will allow no objections!
他にお前達が生き残れる道は
Any other paths of survival
for you have now vanished!
なくなった！
コーネリア総督へは
We must inform Viceroy Cornelia.
こちらから連絡を入れます
政庁に帰り着くまでは…
I'll be contacting her.
Can she hold on till we're
back at the government bureau?
もたないでしょう
She probably won't make it.
シュナイゼル殿下には こちらから
I'll contact Prince Schneizel, then.
Excuse me.
では
くーっ
スザク…
Suzaku...
あ…
ユフィ…
Euphy!
ユフィ 教えて欲しい
Euphy... I want you to tell me.
君は どうしてあんな命令を？
Why did you give that order?
命令？
Order?
なんの事？
What are you talking about?
うっ
そんな事より スザクは
日本人… でしたよね
Never mind that... Suzaku...
You're... Japanese, right?
えっ ああ
Y- Yeah?
うっ
ユフィ
Euphy!
違う
No!
え？
ダメっ
I mustn't...
違う…
No... I mustn't... think such a thing...
そんな事… 考えちゃ いけない…
スザク？
Suzaku?
なんだい？
What?
式典は…
The ceremony...
日本は どうなったかしら？
Is Nippon... Is it all right?
ユフィ 覚えていないのか？
Euphy... You don't remember?
うわぁー！
わぁー わぁ！
日本人よ！
People of Japan!
ブリタニアに虐げられた 全ての民よ！
All people who are
oppressed by Britannia!
私は待っていた！
I have waited!
ブリタニアの不正を影から正しつつ
While I have fought their
injustice from the shadows,
彼らが自らを省みる時が来るのを
I have waited for them to come
to their senses on their own.
But now our aspirations
have been betrayed!
しかし… 私達の期待は裏切られた
虐殺という蛮行で！
With an act of barbarism
that can only be called a massacre!
日本人の皆さんは… 喜んで くれた？
Did I make the people
of Japan happy?
ユーフェミアを許すな
Never forgive Euphemia!
卑怯者がぁ
Cowardly murderer!
Never forgive Euphemia!
Witch!
魔女め
嘘つき
Liar!
Witch!
そう！　ユーフェミアこそ
ブリタニア偽善の象徴
That's right! Euphemia is the
symbol of Britannian hypocrisy!
国家という体裁を取り繕った 人殺しだ
A murderer who used the appearance
of a nation to cover up her crime!
私は… うまく できた？
Did I...
Did I make it work?
地獄へ落ちろユーフェミアぁ！
Burn in hell, Euphemia!
もう騙されないぞー！
We won't be fooled again!
ブリタニアに死を！
Death to Britannia!
ユフィ 行政特区は
Euphy... The special zone is...
大成功だ みんな…
とても喜んでいたよ 日本に
It's a huge success!
Everyone is so happy... in Nippon.
良かったぁ
Thank God...
Here and now, I declare our
independence from Britannia!
私は今ここに ブリタニアからの
独立を宣言する
だが それは
かつての日本の復活を意味しない
But don't take this to mean the
resurrection of the old nation of Japan!
歴史の針を戻す愚を 私は犯さない
I won't make the mistake of trying
to wind back the clock of history!
我らが これから作る新しい日本は
The new Japan
we will now build...
あらゆる人種 歴史 主義を
受け入れる広さと
shall be one broad enough to accept all
peoples, all histories, and all ideologies!
強者が弱者を虐げない享受を持つ国家だ
A proud nation where the strong
shall not oppress the weak!
その名は 合衆国日本！
And it shall be called...
THE UNITED STATES OF JAPAN!
うわー！
そうです 今が建国の時
Yes... This moment,
a new nation is born!
おかしいな あなたの顔 見えない
How... strange...
I can't see... your face... anymore...
はぁ…
学校 行ってね 私は… 途中…
やめちゃった… から
Keep going... to school...
I had... to stop... before I finished...
ユフィ 今からでも行けるよ
Euphy... You can still go!
そうだ！
一緒に アッシュフォード学園に行こう
I know! We can both go
to Ashford Academy, together!
楽しい生徒会があるんだ
Their student council is
so much fun! You and I!
君と…
You'll have to... do it... in my place...
私の… 分まで… ね
ダメだ！　ユフィ ダメだ！
No! Euphy, don't!
はぁ スザク… あなたに 会えて…
Suzaku...
I'm so glad... I was able to...
はあ…
Zero! Zero! Zero! Zero!
ゼロ ゼロ ゼロ ゼロ…
そんな…
No...
CODE GEASS
Lelouch of the Rebellion
エリア フクシマ 白虎分隊
イバラキに向けて進行中
Area Fukushima, Byakko squad,
en route to Ibaraki.
Area Tama, barricade construction
by unarmed civilians is continuing.
エリア タマ ヒブソン非民による
バリケード作業続行中
トウキョウ租界に攻め込むつもりか？
You're planning to assault
the Tokyo settlement?
ああ　今が最大のチャンス
Right. This is the best chance we'll get.
あっ
大丈夫だ 私にギアスは効かない
知っているだろう？
It's all right. Geass doesn't work on me.
You know that, don't you?
そうだったな ふっ
That's true, isn't it?
ギアスの制御ができない以上
みんなとは もうお別れか
Now that I can't control my Geass,
I suppose I can never see the others again.
ん？
ナナリー
Nunnally?
Big brother? I was wondering...
Could I speak with Euphy again?
お兄様 あの…
ユフィ姉様と お話ししたくって
なっ
私とお兄様と３人で学園祭を…
You and me and her,
at the school festival.
You see, Milly said they're going
to hold another school festival,
ほら ミレイさんが中断した学園祭
もう一度やるんだって言ってましたよね
since the last one was interrupted.
だから その時は一緒にどうかな～って
So, I was wondering if we could
all get together at that one, too.
あの ごめんなさい
もう会わないって言ったのに…
I mean, I'm sorry to ask. I know you
said we could never meet again.
でも どんな形でもいいから
もう一度だけ 直接会えると
But, if there was some way at all we
could meet directly again, then!
ナナリー 聞いてないのか？　ニュース
Nunnally, haven't you heard
what happened on the news?
ラジオは途中で放送が終わってしまって
The radio suddenly cut off during the
broadcast. Did something happen?
何かあったんですか？
いや… だったらいいんだ
No. That's all right.
ごめん 明日には帰るから
それから相談しよう
I'm sorry. I'll be home tomorrow.
I'll discuss it with you then.
Right.
うん
ギアスの切り替えができなくなった他に
変化はないか？
Have there been any other changes,
aside from losing control of your Geass?
別に… ただ
Not particularly. Just...
ユフィは 俺のギアスに
命令に逆らおうとした
Euphy... She resisted the Geass.
My orders...
能力が落ちたのか とも思ったが
I was wondering if my power
had weakened, but...
それは 多分…
But, I think it was...
She couldn't forgive such an order.
彼女にとって とても許せない事で
とても 当たり前の事で
It was so against her nature...
And so?
それで？
それだけだ… ひょっとした…
That's all.
It was just...
契約したろ お前の傍にいると
私だけは…
I made my contract with you.
At the very least, I'll stay with you to the end.
We were too slow.
後手に回りました
ネット情報はカットしたものの
Even though we've cut off the
news being spread on the Net,
僅か数時間のうちに
各地で暴動が発生しています
insurrections have broken out
in all areas in just a few hours!
最大の武装勢力 黒の騎士団は
一般民衆を吸収しつつ
The largest armed group,
the Black Knights,
are absorbing the masses and
advancing on the Tokyo settlement!
このトウキョウ租界を目指して進軍中！
他のブロックは防戦に回っており
援軍は望めません
The other blocks have deployed forces for
defense and can't send reinforcements!
敵の勢力は
寝返った名誉ブリタニア人も加え
Counting betrayals
by honorary Britannians,
その数は数万を超えます
the enemy's strength now reaches
into the tens of thousands!
Lord Guilford!
ギルフォード卿
No! We cannot move without
orders from Her Highness!
ダメだ！　殿下の命令なしに
動くことはできぬ
しかし！　総督は
攻撃中止命令を出されたのち
But sir! The viceroy's been shut
up in Princess Euphemia's room...
ユーフェミア様の居室におこもりに…
ever since she canceled
the attack orders!
ダールトン将軍も
行方不明という状況では
Not to mention we still can't
confirm Gen. Darlton's whereabouts!
うーん
うっ はーっ う… はぁー
こちら トヤマ分隊 23名 合流する
This is Toyama squad. There are
23 of us. We'll link up with you.
Roger that. Do you have any weaponry?
了解　武装は なしか
オカヤマから 爆薬を調達した
車両が足りない 何名か分乗できないか
We got explosives from Gokayama.
We lack transports, though.
Can some of us ride on your transports?
あいてるのは貨物車だけだ
それでいいか？
The only empty transports we have
are freight trains? Will that be okay?
ヤマナシのグループも
合流するってさぁ
The groups from Yamanashi
have linked up with us, too!
サムライの血の生き残りからも
連絡があった
We've also gotten word from
survivors of the Samurai Blood group.
ものすごい数になるぞ
Our numbers are becoming huge now!
生徒会のみんな…
逃げてくれてると いいけど
I hope the other student
council members can get away.
そんな事はない 喜んでいるさ 私は
No, that's not true at all.
I'm glad for this.
あぁ 優しさなんか
忘れてしまったんだよ マリアンヌ
Yeah... I forgot kindness
a long time ago, Marianne.
I hope you're all right, Mr. Kaname.
要さんの方こそ大丈夫？
確かシズオカで仕事だって
You said you had work in Shizuoka.
あぁ こっちはなんとか
Yeah, I'm fine over here.
なぁ 千草
帰ったら大事な話があるんだが
Look, Chigusa, we have something
important to discuss when I get back.
はあ…
ん どうした？
Hm? What's up?
初めて その名前で呼んでくれましたね
That's the first time you've
ever called me by that name.
あぁ… すまない 変だったかな？
Oh, you're right.
Does it sound weird to you?
いいえ それじゃあ 待ってます
Not a bit!
Anyway, I'll be waiting.
あっ！
いたぞー！　ブリキの女だー！
There she is! It's the Brit woman!
さっき外見てただろう
I just saw her looking outside!
A spy! You're a spy, aren't you?!
スパイだ！　スパイだな？
はっ…
反乱軍の接近により
ゲットーの治安が悪化しています
As the insurgents draw closer, security
in the ghettos continues to worsen.
市民の皆さんは
政府より通達があるまで
The government is asking all citizens to
remain in their homes until further notice.
家から出ないように お願いします
ここも 戦場になるのでしょうか…
Do you think the fighting
will come here, too?
うっ まさかぁ コーネリア総督の
正規軍がいるんだぜ？　ないないっ
N-No way! Princess Cornelia has her regular
forces stationed here. There's no way!
You think so?
そうかなぁ
んな事言うなよ 怖いだろ？
Don't sound like that, will you?
You're scaring me!
Nunnally, isn't Lelouch home yet?
ナナリー まだ帰って来てないの？
ルルーシュは
ル… ルルーシュ？
Lelouch?
どうかしました？
Is something wrong?
あっ 別に
No, not really...
なぁ いい加減 ルルって呼べよぉ
仲直りしてさ
Oh, c'mon. Can't you make up
and go back to calling him Lulu?
ルル？　私 そう呼んでたの？
Lulu? I called him that?
また そんな事言って
Oh, there you go again!
ルル
Lulu...
ニーナ 校舎フロアに戻って！
反乱軍がトウキョウに迫ってるのよ？
Nina, they want us back
at the school building floor!
The insurgents are
approaching Tokyo!
知ってる ゼロが来るんだよね
I know. Zero's coming, isn't he?
あ…
待っていて下さい ユーフェミア様
私が必ず 仇を討ちますから
Please wait for me, Princess Euphemia.
I swear, I'll avenge you!
ユフィ 僕には分からないよ
どうして君があんな事を…
Euphy...
I just don't understand.
Why did you give that order?!
Shall I tell you?
教えてあげようか？
あっ
へっ？　子供？
A child? What are you
doing aboard the Avalon?
どうして アヴァロンに
初めまして 枢木スザク
How do you do, Suzaku Kururugi.
My name is V.V....
僕の名前は V.V.
V.V.？
V.V.?
They've broken
the Atsugi line, as well!
アツギラインも突破された
Can we get reinforcements
from the homeland?
本国からの増援を
もう 間に合わん
They'll never make it in time.
Then we should abandon
this area for now...
では このエリアを一先ず捨てて
うろたえるな！
Don't panic!
なっ
コ… コーネリア様
P-Princess Cornelia!
I've put the Glaston Knights
on standby.
グラストンナイツを待機させた
全軍 トウキョウ租界外縁に陣を敷け！
Deploy all of our forces on the
outer edge of the Tokyo settlement!
黒の騎士団を
ゼロさえ潰せば反乱は治まる！
If we crush the Black Knights, or just kill Zero,
then this insurrection will collapse!
コーネリアさえ倒せば 我々の勝ちだ
If we can just kill Cornelia,
then we win!
All forces, follow the deployment
scheme and stand by!
全軍！　作戦配置図に従い 待機せよ
ディートハルト 前線は藤堂に
Diethard, have Tohdoh
handle the front line.
ここはお前に任せる
I'm leaving you in charge here.
分かりました
Understood, sir.
あっ
皇の…
You're Sumeragi's?
良かった 間に合いました
Oh, thank goodness!
I'm in time!
ひどいなぁ 私をおいて
さっさと出陣しちゃうなんて
That was so mean of you, going into battle
and then leaving me behind like that!
私 ずーっとファンだったんですよ
あなたのデビューから
I've been a fan of yours for a
while now, ever since your debut!
ようやく ちゃ～んとお話できると
思ったのに
I was hoping we could finally
have a chance to talk, but...
背 意外と高いんですね
You're much taller
than most people, huh?
でも大丈夫 すぐに追いつきますから
Don't worry,
I'll catch up with you soon.
かっ 神楽耶様
六家の方々はフジに残られたはずでは？
L-Lady Kaguya, I thought the heads of
the Six Houses are staying back at Fuji.
I caught up with you!
To see how my future husband fights!
追いかけて来たの
夫の戦いぶりを見る為にねっ
えぇっ？
お戯れを
Please don't joke.
When you win this battle,
you'll eventually need a wife, right?
この戦いに勝利したら
いずれ妻が必要になりましょう？
あなたが素顔を見せられない身の上なら
それを補う者がいると思いますが？
If you're never going
to show your face to anyone,
I think you're going to need
someone to compensate for that.
勝てると思うのですか？　この戦い
You think we're going
to win this battle?
えぇ 私は勝利の女神ですから
Yes! Because I'm the
goddess of victory!
それは頼もしい しかし 残念ながら
私は既に悪魔と契約してしまった
How splendid! Unfortunately,
I've already made a contract with the devil.
え？
今さら神とは 仲良くできませんよ
I'm afraid I can't be friendly
with any gods now.
早くしろ！　本国に実験適合生体を
Hurry! We have to get the experimental
bioform back to the homeland!
Ah! The pressure!
The internal pressure is rising!
圧力が！
あっ
内圧が上昇中…
おわっ あぁー
うぅっ こ こんな時に
Now, of all times!
おはようございました
Good morning, sir.
聞くがよい ブリタニアよ
我が名はゼロ
Hear me, Britannia!
My name is Zero!
A rebel against those
who possess power!
力ある者に対する 反逆者である
０時まで待とう 降伏し我が軍門に下る
We will wait until midnight.
You have until then to surrender to me.
これは最終通告だ
０時まで待つ 我が軍門に下れ
This is your last warning.
You have until midnight
to surrender to us!
ぬう…
ダールトン将軍 やはり無理では
Gen. Darlton, please!
You're in no condition to do this!
構わぬ 姫様を… 姫様の元に…
I don't care! Her Highness...
I must get to Her Highness!
無駄な脅しだな ゼロ
トウキョウ租界は城塞都市でもあるのだ
A useless bluff, Zero.
The Tokyo settlement
was built to be a fortress city.
You can still turn back.
今なら まだ戻れるぞ？
このままではエリア11だけでは済まない
After this, it won't just
stop here in Area 11.
この世界全体が
お前の命が戦いに染まる
The entire world and your very
life will become steeped in battle.
分かっている　だが 俺は…
I know that. But, I...
なっ
あっ！
ユフィ？　バカなっ
あいつの番号など…
Euphy?!
Impossible! I never called her...
いや 語っている奴がいる
No, there is one who'd
be calling in her place...
チッ
ルルーシュ 僕だよ
Lelouch? It's me.
スザクか どうした？　こんな時に
Suzaku? Why are you
calling at a time like this?
ルルーシュ 今 学校？
Lelouch... Are you at school now?
いや でも もうすぐ帰るよ
No, but I'll be back there soon.
そう 電話をしたのは
みんなに伝えて欲しい事があって
I see. I called because there's
something I want to tell everyone.
なんだい？　こんな時に
What, especially now?
空を… 空を見ないで欲しい
The sky...
I don't want you to look up into the sky.
え？
What?
ルルーシュ 君は 殺したいと思うほど
憎い人がいるかい？
Lelouch...
Is there anyone you hate so
much that you want to kill them?
ああ いる
Yeah, there is.
そんなふうに考えては
いけないと思っていた
I used to think it was
wrong to think that way.
ルールに従って戦わなければ
それは ただの人殺しだって…
That unless you fought
following rules, it was just murder.
でも 今 僕は憎しみに支配されている
But now...
Hatred has taken control of me.
人を殺す為に 戦おうとしている
I'm fighting now to kill someone.
みんながいるトウキョウの空の上で
人殺しを
I'm going to become a murderer in the skies of
Tokyo, where all my friends live. That's why!
だから…
You should hate.
憎めばいい
うっ
ユフィの為だろ？
それに 俺はもう とっくに決めたよ
For Euphy's sake. Besides,
I made up my mind a long time ago.
引き返すつもりはない
I have no intention
of turning back now.
ナナリーの為？
For Nunnally's sake?
ああ
Yeah.
切るぞ そろそろ
I have to go now.
ありがとう ルルーシュ
Thank you, Lelouch.
気にするな 俺達 友達だろ？
Forget it.
We're friends, aren't we?
７年前からずっと
For the last seven years.
ああ じゃあな
Yeah. I'll see you.
それじゃ あとで
Okay. See you later.
何！
What?!
スザク 俺の手はとっくに
汚れてるんだよ
Suzaku, I dirtied my hands
a long time ago.
それでも向かってくるなら構わない
Even so, your coming
to face me doesn't matter.
I'll welcome you.
歓迎してやるさ 俺達は友達だからな
After all, we're friends,
aren't we?
ふっふふふ
はっはははっ
はっはははっ…
Perhaps this was what
I had hoped for since that day.
あの日から 俺はずっと
望んでいたのかもしれない
あらゆる破壊と喪失を
The destruction
and loss of everything.
そう 創造の前には破壊が必要だ
That's right.
Destruction is necessary before creation.
その為に心が邪魔になるのなら
消し去ってしまえばいい
So, anything that may make my heart
waver from that should be swept away.
そうだ
That's right.
The only path left to me is forward.
俺はもう進むしかない
だから
And so...
モザイクカケラ ひとつひとつ
Mosaic kakera
The pieces of a mosaic
Hitotsu hitotsu tsunagiawasete
Coming together one by one
繋ぎ合わせて描いてゆく
Egaiteyuku
To form the picture
あなたがくれた 出逢いと別れも
Anata ga kureta deai to wakare mo
The meetings and partings I've had with you
こんなはずじゃない そう思って眠り
Konna hazu ja nai
"It can't be," I think
Sou omotte nemuri
As I go to sleep
Mezamereba itsumo no
When I awaken, just as always
目覚めればいつもの 変わらない空回り
Kawaranai karamawari
I'm left going nowhere
意味も無く繰り返し
Imi mo naku kurikaeshi
Pointlessly repeating the pattern
モザイクカケラ 鮮やかに映す
Mosaic kakera
The pieces of a mosaic
Azayaka ni utsusu
Clearly showing
過去の嘘も過ちも
Kako no uso mo ayamachi mo
The lies and mistakes of the past
消してしまいたいと想えば想うほど
Keshiteshimaitai to omoeba omou hodo
As much as I'd like to erase them
振り返れば
Furikaereba soko ni aru
When I look back, I see...
そこにあるスタートライン
Start line mada susun ja inai
I still haven't moved past that start line
未だ進んじゃいない
もう一度夢を拾い集めてみよう
Mou ichido yume wo
So let's try regathering
Hiroiatsumete miyou
the pieces of our dream
モザイクカケラ ひとつひとつ
Mosaic kakera
The pieces of a mosaic
Hitotsu hitotsu tsunagiawasete
Coming together one by one
繋ぎ合わせて描いてゆく
Egaiteyuku
To form the picture
あなたがくれた 出逢いと別れも
Anata ga kureta deai to wakare mo
The meetings and partings I've had with you
ああ そうだ
That's right. Only by going
forward will I find atonement.
進む事だけが 俺の贖罪
たとえ相手が世界最大の帝国であろうと
Even if my enemy is the
greatest empire on the planet,
there's no turning back
for me now!
もはや 俺に振り返るべき道はない
策は全て完成している
Everything is in place
for the plan.
今こそ 古き物を打破する時
The time has come to
sweep away the old order!
THE COLLAPSING STAGE